Mss.Rec.87 Mss.Rec.87
American Philosophical Society
Stoney (Assiniboine) texts taken at Stoney Reserve, Morley, Alberta; January 1, 1968 - August 21-23, 1971
1968, 1971
Mss.Rec.87
American Philosophical Society
3.0 Reel(s)
This collection consists of one tape of a New Years' Service held at a Community Hall on 1 January 1968, and two tapes of autobiographical stories, folkloric stories, tribal histories, and descriptions of customs given in the Stoney language only by Carl Simeon (identified as a "speaker of the younger dialect") on 21 August 1971 and by Willie Good Stoney (identified as a "speaker of theh older dialect") on 23 August 1971.
3 sound tape reels (52 min.): analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
Rider, Dillon
SImeon, Carl
Snow, John
Stoney, William Good
Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
Wesley, Lazarus
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Allan R. Taylor in 1972 (Acc.1972 636ms). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Transcriptions and translations of the texts on these recordings can be found in Phillips Fund collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Assiniboine Indians--Education; Assiniboine Indians--First contact with Europeans; Assiniboine Indians--Folklore; Assiniboine Indians--Food; Assiniboine Indians--History; Assiniboine Indians--Religion; Assiniboine Indians--Social life and customs; Canada. Treaties, etc. 1877 September 22; Cree language; Indian sign language; Indians of North America--Alberta--History; Sarsi language; Siksika Indians; Siksika language; Sound recordings; Stoney language
- Audio recordings
  - New Years' service at Community Hall, 1971-08-24; 1968-01-01; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:10; Harbeck, Warren A.; Rider, Dillon; Snow, John; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-; Wesley, Lazarus
    Scope and Contents note
    A transcription of this program in Stoney and an English translation are available in the collector's documentation.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Assiniboine Indians--Religion; Assiniboine Indians--Social life and customs; Morley (Alta.); New Year sermons; Prayers; Stoney language
  - Band Council, Culture, 1971-08-21; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:13; Simeon, Carl; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    A text given in Stoney (Nakoda) only by Carl Simeon, identified as a "speaker of younger dialect." Introduced in English by the collector. A transcription of this text in Stoney and an English translation are available in the collector's documentation.
    Assiniboine Indians--Education; Assiniboine Indians--Kings and rulers; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - Life Story, 1971-08-21; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; Simeon, Carl; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    A text given in Stoney (Nakoda) only by Carl Simeon, identified as a "speaker of younger dialect." A transcription of this text in Stoney and an English translation are available in the collector's documentation.
    Assiniboine Indians; Autobiography; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - History, 1971-08-21; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; Simeon, Carl; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Indian sign language; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - What kind of love they have, 1971-08-21; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:17; Simeon, Carl; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Assiniboine Indians; Morley (Alta.); Siksika Indians; Stoney language
  - Different languages, 1971-08-21; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Simeon, Carl; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Cree language; Morley (Alta.); Sarsi language; Siksika language; Stoney language
  - History, 1971-08-23; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:44; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    A text given in Stoney (Nakoda) only by Willie Good Stoney, identified as a "speaker of older dialect." Introduced in English by collector. A transcription of this text in Stoney and an English translation are available in the collector's documentation.
    Assiniboine Indians--History; Assiniboine Indians--Religion; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - How they eat, 1971-08-23; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:30; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    A text given in Stoney (Nakoda) only by Willie Good Stoney, identified as a "speaker of older dialect." A transcription of this text in Stoney and an English translation are available in the collector's documentation.
    Assiniboine Indians--Food; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - Indians, 1971-08-23; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:12; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Assiniboine Indians; Cree Indians; Indians of North America--Alberta--History; Morley (Alta.); Siksika Indians; Stoney language
  - Treaty Number 7, 1971-08-23; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:24; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
  - Why they live in this reserve, 1971-08-23; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Assiniboine Indians--Social life and customs; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - How the first whitemen came, 1971-08-23; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:36; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Assiniboine Indians--First contact with Europeans; Assiniboine Indians--History; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language
  - Iktûmî, 1971-08-23; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:13; Stoney, Will Good; Taylor, Allan R. (Allan Ross), 1931-
    Assiniboine Indians--Folklore; Bears--Folklore; Morley (Alta.); Stoney language